Fred C. Kelly Papers
Fred C. Kelly Papers
- Writings
  - Articles
    - "Saving a Circus Parade" (Box 11)
    - "Seek Not Blue Ribbons But Traits,", 2 copies (Box 11)
    - "The Shoestring Headline," printed in Coronet, October, 1939 (Box 11)
    - "Short Cuts to Friend-Making," printed in Coronet, May, 1939 (Box 11)
    - "Simplify Your Letter Writing," reprint from Coronet, July, 1939; 5 copies (Box 11)
    - "The Social Lobby in Washington," printed in The Dearborn Independent, May 14, 1927; 2 copies (Box 11)
    - "A Soft Spot For Hardware," printed in The Rotarian, December, 1958; includes first proof copy; 5 copies (Box 11)
    - "Speeding Up Your Senses," printed in Cosmopolitan, October, 1921; 2 copies (Box 11)
    - "Spotting Fraud in Documents" (Box 11)
    - "Strokes, The Methodical," printed in All-Story Weekly (Box 11)
    - "The Story of the Rise of the Kerosene King", galley with corrections (Box 11)
    - "Suckers in Oil" (Box 11)
    - "Tabloid Detective Tales" (Box 11)
    - "A Talk With Henry Ford" (Box 11)
    - "Teach Yourself to Travel," printed in Coronet, March, 1939 (Box 11)
    - "That Molineux Murder Case,", 3 copies (Box 11)
    - "They're Wondering What You'll Read" (Box 11)
    - "This Ambassador's a Real Democrat" (Box 11)
    - "Thoughts on Waste Effort," printed in Coronet, January, 1938 (Box 11)
    - "To Find Dog Intelligence," printed copy in Esquire, August, 1939 (Box 11)
    - "Understanding Your Dog," printed in The Dearborn Independent, May 28, 1927; 2 copies (Box 11)
    - "Want to Live on a Farm?" printed in Coronet, August, 1952 (Box 11)
    - "We Americans in Europe," printed in Coronet, November, 1939 (Box 11)
    - "We Can All Be Detectives" (Box 11)
    - "We Can Read Ourselves Educated" (Box 11)
    - "We Have With Us This Evening" (Box 11)
    - "Weather For U.S. Army" (Box 11)
    - "Weather Wise for Merchandise," printed in The American Legion Monthly, September, 1932 (Box 11)
    - "What Happens When You Sell Short" (Box 11)
    - "What Hokum do You Practice?" (Box 11)
    - "What Makes Girls 'Bad' and 'Good'," printed copy (Box 11)
    - "What Technocracy Means to the Utilities," printed in Public Utilities Fortnightly, February 2, 1933 (Box 11)
    - "Wheels and the Law" (Box 11)
    - "When All Highways Were Disgraceful," printed in Michigan Alumnus, May, 1957; 2 copies (Box 11)
    - "When Grunewald Was a Spy Chaser,", 3 versions (Box 11)
    - "When Old Boys Succeed With Young Women" (Box 11)
    - "When the Senate Opens," printed in Harper's Weekly, May, 1914 (Box 11)
    - "When You Get Up to Talk," printed in Coronet, August, 1939 (Box 11)
    - "Where Science Overtakes Criminals" (Box 12)
    - "Where to Watch Your Step in Stocks" (Box 12)
    - "Which Words Do You Use Most?" printed in The American Magazine (Box 12)
    - "Who Lands Good Jobs - And Why", 2 copies (Box 12)
    - "Who Shall Spend Your Money?" printed in Collier's, Feb. 2, 1924 (Box 12)
    - "Why Criminals Can Be Taught" (Box 12)
    - "Why Gossips Are Good Neighbors" (Box 12)
    - "Why I Am Pro-Russian," reprint from Digest and Review Magazine, 1944; 3 copies (Box 12)
    - "Wine Detective," printed copy from Coronet, April, 1937 (Box 12)
    - "A Woman's Grip" (Box 12)
    - "You Always Can Tell," printed in The American Legion, April,1932 (Box 12)
    - "Your Dog's Instincts," printed in The Dearborn Independent, June 11, 1927 (Box 12)
    - "Your Strategy on a Trip to Europe," European Travels, 1933-1934; 18 manuscripts (Box 12)
    - Duplicates (Box 22-24)
    - Untitled manuscripts
      - by Peter Grim as told to Fred C. Kelly (Box 12)
      - by pseudonyms
        - Allison, Oscar (Box 12)
        - Hicks, Elwood (Box 12)
        - Miscellaneous short articles, 1917 - 1953 (Box 12)
        - Fragments of articles (Box 12)
  - Books
    - American Adventure (Box 12)
    - The Bastard Who Invaded England, typescript carbon, 2 copies; typescript, final; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - The Best of Kin Hubbard, collected by Kelly (Box 13)
    - The Bicycle Book, Chapters I-IV, incomplete, 2 versions (Box 14)
    - George Ade (Box 14)
    - The Life and Times of Kin Hubbard (Box 14)
    - My Father, Santa Claus and Me
      - Proof sheets, 1958 (Box 14)
      - Published edition in slipcase, 1958; hand-colored illustrations on cover and title page; inscribed and dedicated to John S. Mayfield (Oversize 1)
    - One Born Every Minute
      - Chapters I-XIX (Box 14)
      - Chapters XX-XXXIV (Box 15)
      - Chapters I-XVII, section 1 (Box 15)
      - Chapters XVIII-XXXIII, section 2 (Box 15)
      - Incomplete version (Box 15)
    - Seeing Russia is Fun (Box 15)
    - Untitled European trip (Box 16)
    - Chapters, extracts, fragments, 1933 (Box 16)
  - Columns
    - Kellygrams
      - Proofs, 1925; 1926,; 1927,; 1929; 2 folders (Box 16)
      - Proofs and manuscripts, undated (Box 16)
    - Nation's Business, printed, 1925-1932 (Box 16)
  - Newspapers
    - The Omnigraph, high school paper edited by Kelly, holograph and printed, 1896; 1899 (Box 16)
  - Notebooks
    - School chemistry (Box 16)
    - School English (Box 16)
    - School English history (Box 16)
    - Story ideas (Box 17)
  - Notes
    - General (Box 17)
  - Outlines
    - General (Box 17)
  - Playlets
    - The Country Editor, 1913 (Box 17)
  - Poems
    - General (Box 17)
  - Press releases
    - "Abroad at Home", 1935 (Box 17)
  - Short story
    - Untitled (Box 17)
  - Speeches
    - General, 1900 (Box 17)
  - Writings of others
    - Articles about Kelly
      - Duplicates (Box 22-24)
    - Brownell, William C., untitled manuscript (Box 17)
    - Chapman, William Carlton, T. Jefferson Plum, Unofficial Diplomatist (Box 17)
    - Corey, Herbert
      - Article (Box 17)
      - Books, A Hard Old Man and It's Been a Good Show (Box 17)
    - Hubbard, Kin, article, "Kin Hubbard Autobiography" (Box 18)
    - Kelly, William Byron, article (Box 18)
    - Post, Geoffrey, article (Box 18)
    - Sale, Charles (Chic), article (Box 18)
- Photographs
  - Animals, 1895; 1896 (Box 18)
  - Deming, Zell Hart, inscribed to Fred Kelly (Oversize 1)
  - Europe, 1934; 1946 (Box 18)
  - Friends, 1927; 1933 (Box 18)
  - Homes, buildings (Box 18)
  - Kelly, adult, 1920; 1929 (Box 18)
  - Kelly and friends, 1909; 1956,; 1958 (Box 18)
  - Kelly, infant and child, 1894 (Box 18)
  - Kelly, young man, 1904 (Box 18)
  - Kelly's mother (Oversize 1)
  - Kelly, parents and grandparents, brother, 1889; 1904 (Box 18)
  - Tintypes and very early photos (Box 18)
  - Wife and children, 1955 (Box 18)
  - Unidentified (Box 18)
  - Unidentified man in hat (Oversize 1)
- Wright Brothers material
  - Correspondence to Kelly
    - From Orville Wright, 1939-1948 (Box 19)
    - From Milton Wright, 1951 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence of Orville and Wilbur Wright to and from others, and to each other, photostats, 1895-1946 (Box 19)
  - Clippings
    - About the Wrights, 1943-1953 (Box 20)
    - Book reviews
      - How We Invented the Airplane, by O. Wright, introduction by F. C. Kelly, 1953-1954 (Box 20)
      - Miracle at Kitty Hawk, by F. C. Kelly, 1951 (Box 20)
      - The Wright Brothers, by F. C. Kelly, 1943-1945 (Box 20)
  - Diagrams, Kitty Hawk, 1906; 1913 (Box 20)
  - Flight, research material, 1904-1949 (Box 20)
  - Langley Affair, 1921-1944 (Box 20)
  - Legal documents, 1948; 1951 (Box 20)
  - Maps (Box 20)
  - Photographs, 1897-1909; 1948 (Box 20)
  - Writings about the Wrights by F. C. Kelly
    - Articles, manuscript and printed, 1940-1953 (Box 21)
    - Book, The Wright Brothers
      - Galley proof (Box 21)
      - Page proof (one page) (Box 21)
      - Notes and Synopses, photostats, 1948 (Box 21)
  - Writings about the Wrights by others
    - Articles, photostats and printed material, 1909-1954 (Box 21)
    - Book, The Kitty Hawk, by Rose and Shavelson, mimeographed, 1955 (Box 21)
  - Writings by Orville Wright, printed and photostats, 1889; 1921-1948 (Box 21)
  - Writings by Wilbur Wright, 1902; manuscripts and photostats (Box 21)